<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aubrey Portwood</title>
    <link>https://aubreypwd.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aubrey Portwood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aubreypwd.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Monday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-monday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon  Morning In accordance to my Social Duty, I am sharing my thoughts from my morning exercise. I was highly motivated by Chuck Chakrapani&amp;rsquo;s presentation at Stoicon this year (as you will see). I set out this morning re-defining the virtues for myself, to set my focus for the day and week ahead:
Wisdom: as the lack of foolishness  A stoic is not a fool, for fools often stumble, fall, and grow frustrated and unhappy It would be foolish to fear the unknown, at the risk of doubling your fear It would be foolish to try and control something you absolutely have no control over All other virtues aim and not being the fool, thus calling for wisdom in them all  Courage: as a lack of fear  Replace fear with caution, aware of it, doing only what you can, yet utterly let go of controlling it Fearlessness, then, is at the hexrart of Courage Since you are not in control of everything, you are called to endure those things  Justice: as a lack of social duty  &amp;ldquo;What is not good for the beehive, is not good for the bee,&amp;rdquo; Marcus A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch SE Review</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/apple-watch-se-watch-os-7-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/apple-watch-se-watch-os-7-review/</guid>
      <description>About 2 weeks ago I bought an Apple Watch SE. This is my review/experience so far.
Note that I do not sync things to my watch, as I prefer to play most things directly from my iPhone, just a quick note for the below, as I&amp;rsquo;m not doing any syncing for Music, Audiobooks, and Podcasts.
The Bad Audiobooks &amp;amp; Podcasts Show Wrong Episode As you can see I&amp;rsquo;m listening to The Daily Stoic, but it&amp;rsquo;s showing Stoicism on Fire!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stoic Five-minute Journal</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-five-minute-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 03:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-five-minute-journal/</guid>
      <description>So the last month or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling a little bit different. A while go, I ran across a video that went over the idea of the Five Minute Journal, and I was intrigued.
The idea is you answer a few simple prompts:
 I am grateful for: What would make today great? Daily affirmation. I am: 3 Amazing things that happened today: How could I have made today even better:  &amp;hellip;and I did that for about a week before I felt it lacked a Stoic-seasoning, and so I worked and re-worked that format until I landed on a format that has both accomplish the goal of making journaling a little easier and getting your Stoic practice in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-centralizing my system configurations: dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</guid>
      <description>Note, I&amp;rsquo;ve entirely ditched this system and opted for a new one I will post about later.
 Today I did some experimenting. You see my system is entirely customized to be super-efficient and automated.

As you can see I currently have these housed in a giant Git repository in my ~/.config/. This has worked out just fine for a while, but I wanted to experiment with trying to de-centralize it with some kind of package management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a lot of fun building a new site for aubreypwd.com using Hugo and Github Pages.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a lot of time to work on a website, let alone write content for one. In fact, I used to have a pretty nice site, but I never kept up with it, and eventually just redirected it to Twitter. I also tried out write.as to try and publish content, but I found I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use it a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better words for stoic virtues</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/better-words-for-stoic-virtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 03:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/better-words-for-stoic-virtues/</guid>
      <description>This article was moved from thebadstoic.com, which may no longer be active.
 Traditionally, the words for the four primary virtues of Stoicism are:
 Wisdom Justice Courage Temperance  If you’re about to do a thing, you ask yourself:
 Am I being Wise? Am I being Just? Am I being Courageous? Am I being Temperate?  But, none of these words have ever really meant much for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>