<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aubrey Portwood</title>
    <link>https://aubreypwd.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aubrey Portwood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aubreypwd.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sublime hangs (beachball) on save [Fix]</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/sublime-file-hangs-on-save/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/sublime-file-hangs-on-save/</guid>
      <description>So, the last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve had a thing happen since switching to a MacBook Air recently. Since the CPU is not up to snuff as my old MacBook Pro (more to come on this switch later ⌨️), Sublime Text would hang for about a second on save of a file in a large project.
This likely went un-notice on my 2.7Ghz MacBook Pro, but started to notice it on my Air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Sunday (Monday Makeup)</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-sunday-makeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-sunday-makeup/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon Evening   Morning  The works of the gods are full of providence, and the works of fortune are not separate from nature or the interweaving and intertwining of the things governed by providence. Everything flows from there. Further factors are necessity and the benefit of the whole universe, of which you are a part. What is brought by the nature of the whole and what maintains that nature is good for each part of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Saturday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-saturday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Evening   Morning  Be like the headland, on which the waves break constantly, which still stands firm, while the foaming waters are put to rest around it. ‘It is my bad luck that this has happened to me.’ On the contrary, say, ‘It is my good luck that, although this has happened to me, I can bear it without getting upset, neither crushed by the present nor afraid of the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Friday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-friday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon Evening   Morning  It isn’t the things themselves that disturb people, but the judgements that they form about them. Death, for instance, is nothing terrible, or else it would have seemed so to Socrates too; no, it is in the judgement that death is terrible that the terror lies. Accordingly, whenever we are impeded, disturbed or distressed, we should never blame anyone else but only ourselves, that is, our judgements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Thursday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-thursday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-thursday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon Evening   Morning  It is important to understand that nature creates in parents affection for their children; and parental affection is the source from which we trace the shared community of the human race … As it is obvious that it is natural to us to shrink from pain, so it is clear that we derive from nature itself the motive to love those to whom we have given birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon Evening   Morning  If you can find anything in human life better than justice, truthfulness, self-control, courage turn to it with all your heart and enjoy the supreme good that you have found but if you find all other things to be trivial and valueless in comparison with virtue, give no room to anything else, since, once you turn towards that and divert from your proper path, you will no longer be able without inner conflict to give the highest honour to what is properly good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Week 2020: Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-week-2020-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Morning Afternoon Evening   Morning  Morning Text for Reflection
The wise person does nothing that he could regret, nothing against his will, but does everything honourably, consistently, seriously, and rightly; he anticipates nothing as if it is bound to happen, but is shocked by nothing when it does happen …. and refers everything to his own judgement, and stands by his own decisions. I can conceive of nothing which is happier that this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch SE Review</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/apple-watch-se-watch-os-7-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/apple-watch-se-watch-os-7-review/</guid>
      <description>About 2 weeks ago I bought an Apple Watch SE. This is my review/experience so far.
Note that I do not sync things to my watch, as I prefer to play most things directly from my iPhone, just a quick note for the below, as I&amp;rsquo;m not doing any syncing for Music, Audiobooks, and Podcasts.
The Bad Audiobooks &amp;amp; Podcasts Show Wrong Episode As you can see I&amp;rsquo;m listening to The Daily Stoic, but it&amp;rsquo;s showing Stoicism on Fire!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stoic Five-minute Journal</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-five-minute-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 03:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/stoic-five-minute-journal/</guid>
      <description>So the last month or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling a little bit different. A while go, I ran across a video that went over the idea of the Five Minute Journal, and I was intrigued.
The idea is you answer a few simple prompts:
 I am grateful for: What would make today great? Daily affirmation. I am: 3 Amazing things that happened today: How could I have made today even better:  &amp;hellip;and I did that for about a week before I felt it lacked a Stoic-seasoning, and so I worked and re-worked that format until I landed on a format that has both accomplish the goal of making journaling a little easier and getting your Stoic practice in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-centralizing my system configurations: dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</guid>
      <description>Note, I&amp;rsquo;ve entirely ditched this system and opted for a new one I will post about later.
 Today I did some experimenting. You see my system is entirely customized to be super-efficient and automated.

As you can see I currently have these housed in a giant Git repository in my ~/.config/. This has worked out just fine for a while, but I wanted to experiment with trying to de-centralize it with some kind of package management.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
