<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Aubrey Portwood</title>
        <link>https://aubreypwd.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Aubrey Portwood</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:28:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://aubreypwd.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>👋 Hi there</title>
            <link>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</guid>
            <description>Today I had a lot of fun building a new site for aubreypwd.com using Hugo and Github Pages.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a lot of time to work on a website, let alone write content for one. In fact, I used to have a pretty nice site, but I never kept up with it, and eventually just redirected it to Twitter. I also tried out write.as to try and publish content, but I found I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use it a lot.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I had a lot of fun building a new site for <strong><a href="/">aubreypwd.com</a></strong> using <strong><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a></strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t had a lot of time to work on a website, let alone write content for one. In fact, I used to have a pretty nice site, but I never kept up with it, and eventually just redirected it to Twitter. I also tried out <a href="https://write.as">write.as</a> to try and publish content, but I found I didn&rsquo;t really use it a lot.</p>
<p>The kind of site I&rsquo;ve always wanted is just a simple one: a bit about who I am with links to all the things you can use to find out more about me. Content is sort of a meh—I&rsquo;d rather be coding :)—and I usually blog over <a href="https://webdevstudios.com/author/aubreypwd/">@WebDevStudios</a> anyways.</p>
<p>Really, this isn&rsquo;t even a blog, the only reason I enabled posts is so I could post updates every once in a while&hellip; and maybe content&hellip; but don&rsquo;t hold your breath, I mostly post on <a href="https://twitter.com/aubreypwd">Twitter</a>.</p>
<h2 id="hugo">Hugo?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always wanted a dead-simple site, I also want a site that is totally under version control (content and all). WordPress doesn&rsquo;t do that, Hugo does. Plus, it was fun to learn and use something new, and was much easier than (<em>but similar enought to</em>) <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> to setup. I would hightly recommend it!</p>
<p>This site is going to be much easier to maintain and deploy than a WordPress one. Also, I could write in Markdown natively, which felt warm-and-fuzzy.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
