<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Aubrey Portwood</title>
        <link>https://aubreypwd.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Aubrey Portwood</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:28:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://aubreypwd.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>De-centralizing my system configurations: gitignore and gitconfig.</title>
            <link>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/de-centralize-configs-gitconfig-gitignore/</guid>
            <description>Today I did some experimenting. You see my system is entirely customized to be super-efficient and automated.

As you can see I currently have these housed in a giant Git repository in my ~/.config/. This has worked out just fine for a while, but I wanted to experiment with trying to de-centralize it with some kind of package management.
Today I focused on my .gitconfig and .gitignore files as an experiment with just my &amp;ldquo;dot-files&amp;rdquo;, and this is what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with:</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I did some experimenting. You see my system is entirely customized to be super-efficient and automated.</p>
<p><a href="/images/greenshot-2020-09-18-184905.png"><img src="/images/greenshot-2020-09-18-184905.png" alt="Screenshot of my current .config"></a></p>
<p>As you can see I currently have these housed in a giant Git repository in my <code>~/.config/</code>. This has worked out just fine for a while, but I wanted to experiment with trying to de-centralize it with some kind of package management.</p>
<p>Today I focused on my <code>.gitconfig</code> and <code>.gitignore</code> files as an experiment with just my &ldquo;dot-files&rdquo;, and this is what I&rsquo;ve come up with:</p>
<p>So I wantedo to figure out what package manager is going to best serve me here. After looking at a lot of them, e.g. npm, bpkg, composer, and a slew of others, I settled on spamming Composer. I know my &ldquo;packages&rdquo; are not PHP, but Composer doesn&rsquo;t care about that, plus of all the package managers it&rsquo;s the easiest to install with git repo support (try doing that with npm or other package managers out there), it manages them well in a reliable location, and on top of that with <code>composer-installers</code> I think I can do some really cool magic later on&hellip;</p>
<p>So I settled on Composer, hate me.</p>
<p>So first I got my <code>.gitignore</code> and <code>.gitconfig</code> files into their own packages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/aubreypwd/.gitconfig">https://github.com/aubreypwd/.gitconfig</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/aubreypwd/.gitignore">https://github.com/aubreypwd/.gitignore</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&hellip;that I could now easliy install to a reliable place, <code>~/.composer</code>. Both packages automatically symlink my <code>~/.gitconfig|ignore</code> file for me using the <a href="https://packagist.org/packages/sioweb/ccevent"><code>/sioweb/ccevent</code></a> package. Even if you supply, e.g. a <code>post-package-install</code> script for the package, because you install it as a dependancy those scripts to not fire. But this package, when installed along side it, will look for <code>package-scripts</code> and run those, so I was able to add that to both packages and when you install them that automatically runs and runs a <code>symlink.sh</code> script.</p>
<p>This symlinking solution on install is great because once I install one of these packages, it symlinks my dot-file in <code>$HOME</code> for me, vs me having to do it manually.</p>
<p>So now I can install dot-files individually and I can automate symlinking them!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m very curious how the rest of this experiment is going to go&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hello World</title>
            <link>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/hello-world/</guid>
            <description>Today I had a lot of fun building a new site for aubreypwd.com using Hugo and Github Pages.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a lot of time to work on a website, let alone write content for one. In fact, I used to have a pretty nice site, but I never kept up with it, and eventually just redirected it to Twitter. I also tried out write.as to try and publish content, but I found I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use it a lot.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I had a lot of fun building a new site for <strong><a href="/">aubreypwd.com</a></strong> using <strong><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a></strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t had a lot of time to work on a website, let alone write content for one. In fact, I used to have a pretty nice site, but I never kept up with it, and eventually just redirected it to Twitter. I also tried out <a href="https://write.as">write.as</a> to try and publish content, but I found I didn&rsquo;t really use it a lot.</p>
<p>The kind of site I&rsquo;ve always wanted is just a simple one: a bit about who I am with links to all the things you can use to find out more about me. Content is sort of a meh—I&rsquo;d rather be coding :)—and I usually blog over <a href="https://webdevstudios.com/author/aubreypwd/">@WebDevStudios</a> anyways.</p>
<p>Really, this isn&rsquo;t even a blog, the only reason I enabled posts is so I could post updates every once in a while&hellip; and maybe content&hellip; but don&rsquo;t hold your breath, I mostly post on <a href="https://twitter.com/aubreypwd">Twitter</a>.</p>
<h2 id="hugo">Hugo?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always wanted a dead-simple site, I also want a site that is totally under version control (content and all). WordPress doesn&rsquo;t do that, Hugo does. Plus, it was fun to learn and use something new, and was much easier than (<em>but similar enought to</em>) <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> to setup. I would hightly recommend it!</p>
<p>This site is going to be much easier to maintain and deploy than a WordPress one. Also, I could write in Markdown natively, which felt warm-and-fuzzy.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Better words for stoic virtues</title>
            <link>https://aubreypwd.com/better-words-for-stoic-virtues/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 03:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aubreypwd.com/better-words-for-stoic-virtues/</guid>
            <description>This article was moved from thebadstoic.com, which may no longer be active.
 Traditionally, the words for the four primary virtues of Stoicism are:
 Wisdom Justice Courage Temperance  If you’re about to do a thing, you ask yourself:
 Am I being Wise? Am I being Just? Am I being Courageous? Am I being Temperate?  But, none of these words have ever really meant much for me.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>This article was moved from <em>thebadstoic.com</em>, which may no longer be active.</p>
<hr>
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Traditionally, the words for the four primary virtues of Stoicism are:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li><strong>Wisdom</strong></li>
<li><strong>Justice</strong></li>
<li><strong>Courage</strong></li>
<li><strong>Temperance</strong></li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you’re about to do a thing, you ask yourself:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li>Am I being <strong>Wise</strong>?</li>
<li>Am I being <strong>Just</strong>?</li>
<li>Am I being <strong>Courageous</strong>?</li>
<li>Am I being <strong>Temperate</strong>?</li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But, none of these <em>words</em> have ever really <em>meant</em> much for me<em>. </em>They don’t reach out to me and explain themselves very well. They’re very academic sounding, lofty, and words that don’t guide me towards my next action. Sometimes they leave me asking, <em>what do I even do?</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So, I’ve come up with my own <em>words</em> for these virtues:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:heading {"level":1} -->
<h2 id="0f11">Wisdom → Truth</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What does Wisdom <em>really</em> mean? — <em>I think</em> it means looking at the world clearly and truthfully. It’s all about the correct knowledge of what’s in front of you:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li>What is <em>really</em> happening right now?</li>
<li>Am I truly in danger of being fired? Is this just my mind racing away from me?</li>
<li>What is this person’s story, why are they <em>really </em>acting this way?</li>
<li>Why is this bothering me? Is it really that bothersome? Is <em>it</em> actually bothering me, or is it just my attitude towards this thing?</li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Too often we look at a given situation and judge it almost <em>immediately</em> for face value. Marcus (and Epictetus) tell us to not to <em>trust first appearances</em>, especially within our own mind. I think this is at the heart of <em>Wisdom.</em> It’s the ability to dissect and analyze any given perception or thing for its truth, absent (mostly) of our own judgements and opinions — <em>seeing things for what they truly are</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Marcus asks us, all the time in the <em>Meditations</em>, to wipe our opinions clean and change them <em>right on the spot</em>! But, it would be wrong to think that Marcus is asking us to just have some change of heart out of no-where. To change our opinions, we need <em>knowledge</em> and that knowledge needs to be based on <em>truth</em> and examination.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li>Why am I so upset about the dog digging a hole in the yard, is it really that hard to fix? Is the dog <em>trying</em> to hurt my feelings? I’m acting as if he is!</li>
<li>Is the universe really out to get me? I <em>just</em> got a flat tire because of a nail, and it looks like it fell off a truck on the highway, the guy must have been in a rush for some reason — maybe to get to his next job he dearly needs.</li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It’s the <em>pause</em> you take to look at something for what it <em>really</em> is, not what you <em>think it is. </em>Or, the gall to admit you don’t know enough. With experience this becomes easier, <em>obviously</em>, but nothing stops us from pausing and acting when we feel we have the truth of the matter<em>, </em>or admitting that we don’t have all the information to act.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:heading {"level":1} -->
<h2 id="d236">Justice → Service</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Justice, if you’re like me, comes off very <em>noble (rightfully so) </em>and <em>legislative,</em> and more concerned about <em>weighing</em> what is right and wrong instead of what actually <em>is</em> right and wrong. In the books of the Stoics, Justice comes off more personal and neighborly to me. I use a version of the <em>Golden Rule</em> as a reminder:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Serve others the way you would serve yourself</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It’s a <em>reflective</em> virtue.<em> It comes with a built-in manual</em>: if you want something <em>for</em> <em>yourself</em>, ensure <em>others</em> get it as well!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li>You want “me-time?” Give others “me-time”!</li>
<li>If you want to be understood, try and understand others.</li>
<li>If you hate doing the dishes, don’t expect others to enjoy doing the dishes.</li>
<li>If you want to be wealthy, help others be wealthy!</li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The word s<em>erve</em> is important, because it’s not enough to just to “<em>treat</em> others the way you would want to be treated” (which implies that you only do this when you come into contact with them), but <em>serving</em> someone with justice is a <em>duty</em> and asks of you to <em>go out</em> and help others gain the very things <em>you</em> want out of life.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:heading {"level":1} -->
<h2 id="05a3">Courage → Fearlessness</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Recently I did an entire reading of the entire <em>Meditations</em>, and noted each time a particular theme came up. <em>Fearlessness</em> came up often, <em>like a lot</em>! It came up in a lot of different ways:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:list -->
<ul>
<li>Not caring what other people think of you</li>
<li>Not caring if people blame you for things</li>
<li>Tackling challenging tasks (not fearing them)</li>
<li>Not fearing the future</li>
<li>Not even caring whether you are going to die!</li>
</ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At one point I think Epictetus asks us, basically, to “<em>fear nothing,</em>” since all un-folding of life is <em>intended</em> and <em>natural</em>!<em> S</em>ince life is going to unfold how it unfolds (either by God or just being the way it is), it’s <em>best</em> to not go out whining and complaining, but <em>fearlessly!</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have a mental exercise that helps me ascertain how to <em>fearlessly</em> approach a situation:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2 id="8918">Temperance → Detachment</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Temperance, when you first hear it — it comes off as being cool-headed and patient. These are all good virtues, but <em>how</em> you do that is very hard to discern. In all my studying, I’ve found that the only way to be <em>temperate</em> is to <em>detach from things</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here’s an example (from Epictetus) that I love to exemplify this virtue (paraphrased):</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Life is a banquet. When a platter of delicious food is handed to you, sample it. If you’re waiting for the platter to come to you, do not seek it out, wait for it to come to you. If it never comes, pay no matter to it.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I feel like the central theme here is <em>detachment</em>. “<em>Sample it</em>” he says, which seems to imply actually <em>enjoying things</em> (which is awesome right), but done so in moderated way (e.g. <em>sample</em>). Further reading will show that it’s <em>really</em> the concern of <em>attachment</em> to pleasant things that is being disciplined. The gist of <em>most of the Stoics</em> is that if you continually enjoy nice things, you will develop habits and familiarity with them, which could <em>attach</em> you to said external thing — say if it goes away.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Furthermore, he goes on to instruct that if the platter floats about the room, to not <em>want</em> after it or seek it out. And, even more so, if it never makes its way over to you, or you were accidentally <em>skipped</em>, to pay no matter to it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Detach from things: expectations, outcomes, wealth, behaviors, etc. It doesn’t mean don’t expect anything, or not enjoy a wealth. But <em>sample</em> them, moderately and appropriately, and pay no matter if they don’t even come to you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Don’t be attached to <em>it, </em>whatever <em>it</em> is.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p style="text-align: center;">Find truth, serve others, be fearless, and detach!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
